<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog</id>
    <title>Escape Simulator Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Escape Simulator Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/img/ESIcon.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Versus Update]]></title>
        <id>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2023/08/01/versus-update</id>
        <link href="https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2023/08/01/versus-update"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Always wondered if you were the one with the biggest brain among your friends? Today you'll be able to find out for yourself by challenging them in Escape Simulator's brand-new Versus Update! Rise to the top of the ranks by being the first to solve all the puzzles in one of our many escape rooms. To commemorate this new way to play, we are also adding a truly challenging room that takes place on a quiz show from the 80s.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="100%" height="500" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/weeOjkY0Ais" title="Escape Simulator: Versus Update - Out now!" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe><p>Always wondered if you were the one with the biggest brain among your friends? Today you'll be able to find out for yourself by challenging them in Escape Simulator's brand-new Versus Update! Rise to the top of the ranks by being the first to solve all the puzzles in one of our many escape rooms. To commemorate this new way to play, we are also adding a truly challenging room that takes place on a quiz show from the 80s.</p><p>Finally, we would like to challenge all of our community's incredibly talented room builders to create their own Versus rooms! That's right, <strong>we are kicking off our fourth official Build-A-Room challenge TODAY</strong>! As always, there are some awesome prizes involved. Be sure to keep reading for more information on this new Build-A-Room challenge down below!</p><p>The Versus Update is absolutely huge and it features a new game mode, new rooms, soundtrack, outfits, a few very interesting additions (such as "join random multiplayer lobby" option), and a bunch of fixes. The full massive <strong>changelog is in the bottom of the page</strong>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="but-how-does-it-work">But how does it work?<a href="#but-how-does-it-work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to But how does it work?" title="Direct link to But how does it work?">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Versus Mode" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/lb-84883a0ee98b1dc518bb2d8f1700247e.gif" width="600" height="337" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>As the title implies, in this brand-new Versus Mode, you will be able to take on other players to prove that you are the greatest escape artist. Just like in the regular Co-op Mode, one player will need to host a game to create a lobby for your opponents to join. Once that's settled, you’ll have to select a room that each of you will be tackling individually. You can choose any room you want, even the community rooms made in the in-game room editor!</p><p>Once you've selected and entered a room, the game begins. In order to keep track of how far along your opponents are, we've added an in-game progress bar that shows you exactly whether you're ahead of the game or if you should step it up a notch! This progress bar will allow you to see the exact progress of your opponents. No pressure or anything.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="back-to-the-80s-">Back to the 80s! ✨<a href="#back-to-the-80s-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Back to the 80s! ✨" title="Direct link to Back to the 80s! ✨">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Classic Game Show" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/rooms-52065626059047bd095c366315dfd968.jpg" width="1134" height="344" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>In addition to the new game mode, we are also adding another free room with two different difficulties (the hard one is designed in collaboration with Wollo!) as part of this update! This time, you will find yourself on the set of a classic game show from the 80's. This room was specifically made with Versus Mode in mind, so you can definitely expect a truly challenging room this time around! Finally, we are also adding a brand-new outfit that will come in two different colors; red and blue! Will your team come out on top and steal the show? Only time will tell!</p><h1>Build-A-Room #4: Versus Challenge!</h1><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Versus Challenge" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/challenge-765e56195a31a9030567839efab9bb8b.png" width="700" height="187" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>As mentioned earlier on in this announcement, the next Build-A-Room contest kicks off <strong>RIGHT NOW</strong>! The only condition for this contest? Create your own Versus Room that is explicitly made to have players race against each other. But what can you win? Well, we're glad you asked!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="prizes">Prizes:<a href="#prizes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Prizes:" title="Direct link to Prizes:">​</a></h2><ul><li>The first place winner will earn themselves <strong>$2,000 in cash</strong> + an escape room board game by <em>PostCurious</em>!</li><li>The second and third place winners get <strong>$100 Steam gift card</strong> + an escape room board game by <em>PostCurious</em></li><li>Winner #4-10 get a <strong>$100 Steam gift card</strong>!</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="rules">Rules:<a href="#rules" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Rules:" title="Direct link to Rules:">​</a></h2><ul><li>To submit a room for the competition, post a link to your room in the "#🏆challenges" channel in the <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pine Studio Discord</a>, or you can send a submission via this <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/discussions/18446744073709551615/3806156352192959151/?appid=1435790" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam thread</a>.</li><li>You can only submit one room. Multiple submissions will not be counted.</li><li>Multiple builders can work together on one room together but there will be only one prize for them.</li><li>It has to be a room escape.</li><li>The gameplay should ideally be under 30 minutes, but it could be longer.</li><li>You can make the room as big as you wish.</li><li>You need to record a video walkthrough.</li><li>You are allowed to bug fix your room after submission, but not resubmit an entirely different room.</li><li>Copies of other players' rooms are not eligible.</li><li>Keep it fun/clean! No profanity, racism, hate speech, sexually suggestive, etc. content. Rooms that might be considered offensive in any way or form will be disqualified.</li><li>Pine team will choose the winners this time!</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dates">Dates:<a href="#dates" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Dates:" title="Direct link to Dates:">​</a></h2><ul><li>This Thursday, August 3rd at 8PM CEST, we'll host a <strong>Steam stream with Q&amp;A</strong></li><li>Submissions are open until <strong>August 21st 8AM CEST / 2AM EST</strong></li><li>We'll play and review all the submissions until <strong>August 31st</strong> when we will host a winning ceremony (stream) and announce the winners. More info about the stream later.</li></ul><p>We hope you're all excited for this new challenge and we can't wait to see what all of you will cook up!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="another-mystery-solved">Another mystery solved!<a href="#another-mystery-solved" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Another mystery solved!" title="Direct link to Another mystery solved!">​</a></h2><p>With this update, we have officially unveiled four announcements from our roadmap for 2023! You can find the updated roadmap version below, but what could those other announcements be? 👀</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Roadmap" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/roadmap-697c4d1a187d16fa387a64b1ed7381f0.jpg" width="2883" height="1622" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="time-to-prove-your-worth">Time to prove your worth!<a href="#time-to-prove-your-worth" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Time to prove your worth!" title="Direct link to Time to prove your worth!">​</a></h2><p>We hope you will all enjoy this brand-new game mode and the free Versus room! Are you still looking for some people to challenge in Versus mode? Then you should definitely join our official <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a>. You can also find us over on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PlayEscapeSimulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a> where you can also talk about all things Escape Simulator. We hope to see you there!</p><h1>Full Changelog</h1><details open="" class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="false"><summary><h4>New Content</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>3, 2, 1, Race! Two Versus specific rooms just landed in the game.</li><li>Immerse yourself in Versus mode with new customization options featuring 2 racer outfits.</li><li>Try the new <strong>Random Game finder</strong> if you can't find players to play with.</li><li>Use Versus props in the room editor to create thrilling racing rooms.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor &amp; Workshop</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>New Roulette Logic Prop! Finally some randomness. Activate one random target from the Targets list!</li><li>Camera movement speed setting! Now you can modify the camera movement speed setting while holding right-click and scrolling. Use shift/ctrl while moving to temporarily modify
the speed.</li><li>Added tooltips for all targets. Now you can tell which target is which by setting its Descriptive name and checking the tooltip.</li><li>Right-click prop selection window UX fixes. Modified when the window is closed, how it reacts to other right-clicks, right-clicking over gizmo, and more.</li><li>No more double-clicking after using the prop search field.</li><li>Fixed highlighting hovered props behind the transform gizmo which cannot be selected.</li><li>Fixed some props rotations.</li><li>Fixed some props being in multiple groups.</li><li>Fixed loading older rooms not opening due to wrong serialized data.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Tweaks</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added a new Host screen with additional options.</li><li>Added an option to change lobby options while already in a lobby.</li><li>Added an option to choose game difficulty in the lobby - Normal or Hard.</li><li>Added a new hover outline type that is less intrusive. You can change it in Options -&gt; Hover Effect Type.</li><li>Added interaction when clicking the dial that moves the dial for one step.</li><li>Changed versioning system to one number, removing prefix 1.0. For example, v1.0.27288n became v27288n.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Level Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed game crash when spamming water turning on and off in "The Lab".</li><li>Removed Steam Cats in Time popup in "Cats in time".</li><li>Fixed not exiting zoom on specific locks in "Leonardo's Workshop".</li><li>Fixed the wrong lock click direction in "70's Room" and "Treasure Island".</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Core Game Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed flashing objects when selecting them in the inventory.</li><li>Fixed custom models changing size in certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed invisible items when being dragged in zoom.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you could lose an item when spamming click on a zoomed item while throwing it out.</li><li>Items no longer shrink if you leave zoom while they animate.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you could duplicate an item while spamming E and changing the item via the numpad.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you could end some interactions too soon if you click alt.</li><li>Added an error screen if you try to enter a lobby with corrupted data or the lobby doesn't exist anymore.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>UI Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed Steamdeck UI bugs in the co-op screen.</li><li>Fixed UI bug where some dropdowns would have extra white elements on edges.</li><li>Fixed a rare case of UI overlapping after finishing the room ("Use" was behind room stats on the top right).</li><li>Fixed buttons staying highlighted in the in-game menu when exiting the menu with ESC.</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Pine</name>
            <uri>https://pinestudio.com</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="versus" term="versus"/>
        <category label="update" term="update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2021/07/31/welcome</id>
        <link href="https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2021/07/31/welcome"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Docusaurus Plushie]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/logo-a787db46d61bc18cfaebe975a2b77ee0.png" width="768" height="294" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Welcome to the Escape Simulator Game Blog!</h1><p>In this blog, we aim to provide you with the latest updates, news, and features about Escape Simulator, the ultimate escape room experience. We'll keep you informed about new game updates, captivating rooms, and other exciting developments in the game. Whether you're a seasoned escape artist or a newcomer looking for a brain-teasing challenge, our blog will guide you through the world of Escape Simulator. Join us on this adventure filled with mind-bending puzzles and the thrill of being an escape master. Let's embark on this journey together!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Pine</name>
            <uri>https://pinestudio.com</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="pine" term="pine"/>
        <category label="hello" term="hello"/>
    </entry>
</feed>