<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Escape Simulator Blog</title>
        <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog</link>
        <description>Escape Simulator Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Versus Update]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2023/08/01/versus-update</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2023/08/01/versus-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Always wondered if you were the one with the biggest brain among your friends? Today you'll be able to find out for yourself by challenging them in Escape Simulator's brand-new Versus Update! Rise to the top of the ranks by being the first to solve all the puzzles in one of our many escape rooms. To commemorate this new way to play, we are also adding a truly challenging room that takes place on a quiz show from the 80s.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe width="100%" height="500" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/weeOjkY0Ais" title="Escape Simulator: Versus Update - Out now!" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe><h1>Are you ready for a battle of the brains? 🧠</h1><p>Always wondered if you were the one with the biggest brain among your friends? Today you'll be able to find out for yourself by challenging them in Escape Simulator's brand-new Versus Update! Rise to the top of the ranks by being the first to solve all the puzzles in one of our many escape rooms. To commemorate this new way to play, we are also adding a truly challenging room that takes place on a quiz show from the 80s.</p><p>Finally, we would like to challenge all of our community's incredibly talented room builders to create their own Versus rooms! That's right, <strong>we are kicking off our fourth official Build-A-Room challenge TODAY</strong>! As always, there are some awesome prizes involved. Be sure to keep reading for more information on this new Build-A-Room challenge down below!</p><p>The Versus Update is absolutely huge and it features a new game mode, new rooms, soundtrack, outfits, a few very interesting additions (such as "join random multiplayer lobby" option), and a bunch of fixes. The full massive <strong>changelog is in the bottom of the page</strong>.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="but-how-does-it-work">But how does it work?<a href="#but-how-does-it-work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to But how does it work?" title="Direct link to But how does it work?">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Versus Mode" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/lb-84883a0ee98b1dc518bb2d8f1700247e.gif" width="600" height="337" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>As the title implies, in this brand-new Versus Mode, you will be able to take on other players to prove that you are the greatest escape artist. Just like in the regular Co-op Mode, one player will need to host a game to create a lobby for your opponents to join. Once that's settled, you’ll have to select a room that each of you will be tackling individually. You can choose any room you want, even the community rooms made in the in-game room editor!</p><p>Once you've selected and entered a room, the game begins. In order to keep track of how far along your opponents are, we've added an in-game progress bar that shows you exactly whether you're ahead of the game or if you should step it up a notch! This progress bar will allow you to see the exact progress of your opponents. No pressure or anything.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="back-to-the-80s-">Back to the 80s! ✨<a href="#back-to-the-80s-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Back to the 80s! ✨" title="Direct link to Back to the 80s! ✨">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Classic Game Show" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/rooms-52065626059047bd095c366315dfd968.jpg" width="1134" height="344" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>In addition to the new game mode, we are also adding another free room with two different difficulties (the hard one is designed in collaboration with Wollo!) as part of this update! This time, you will find yourself on the set of a classic game show from the 80's. This room was specifically made with Versus Mode in mind, so you can definitely expect a truly challenging room this time around! Finally, we are also adding a brand-new outfit that will come in two different colors; red and blue! Will your team come out on top and steal the show? Only time will tell!</p><h1>Build-A-Room #4: Versus Challenge!</h1><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Versus Challenge" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/challenge-765e56195a31a9030567839efab9bb8b.png" width="700" height="187" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>As mentioned earlier on in this announcement, the next Build-A-Room contest kicks off <strong>RIGHT NOW</strong>! The only condition for this contest? Create your own Versus Room that is explicitly made to have players race against each other. But what can you win? Well, we're glad you asked!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="prizes">Prizes:<a href="#prizes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Prizes:" title="Direct link to Prizes:">​</a></h2><ul><li>The first place winner will earn themselves <strong>$2,000 in cash</strong> + an escape room board game by <em>PostCurious</em>!</li><li>The second and third place winners get <strong>$100 Steam gift card</strong> + an escape room board game by <em>PostCurious</em></li><li>Winner #4-10 get a <strong>$100 Steam gift card</strong>!</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="rules">Rules:<a href="#rules" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Rules:" title="Direct link to Rules:">​</a></h2><ul><li>To submit a room for the competition, post a link to your room in the "#🏆challenges" channel in the <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pine Studio Discord</a>, or you can send a submission via this <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/discussions/18446744073709551615/3806156352192959151/?appid=1435790" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam thread</a>.</li><li>You can only submit one room. Multiple submissions will not be counted.</li><li>Multiple builders can work together on one room together but there will be only one prize for them.</li><li>It has to be a room escape.</li><li>The gameplay should ideally be under 30 minutes, but it could be longer.</li><li>You can make the room as big as you wish.</li><li>You need to record a video walkthrough.</li><li>You are allowed to bug fix your room after submission, but not resubmit an entirely different room.</li><li>Copies of other players' rooms are not eligible.</li><li>Keep it fun/clean! No profanity, racism, hate speech, sexually suggestive, etc. content. Rooms that might be considered offensive in any way or form will be disqualified.</li><li>Pine team will choose the winners this time!</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dates">Dates:<a href="#dates" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Dates:" title="Direct link to Dates:">​</a></h2><ul><li>This Thursday, August 3rd at 8PM CEST, we'll host a <strong>Steam stream with Q&amp;A</strong></li><li>Submissions are open until <strong>August 21st 8AM CEST / 2AM EST</strong></li><li>We'll play and review all the submissions until <strong>August 31st</strong> when we will host a winning ceremony (stream) and announce the winners. More info about the stream later.</li></ul><p>We hope you're all excited for this new challenge and we can't wait to see what all of you will cook up!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="another-mystery-solved">Another mystery solved!<a href="#another-mystery-solved" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Another mystery solved!" title="Direct link to Another mystery solved!">​</a></h2><p>With this update, we have officially unveiled four announcements from our roadmap for 2023! You can find the updated roadmap version below, but what could those other announcements be? 👀</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Roadmap" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/roadmap-697c4d1a187d16fa387a64b1ed7381f0.jpg" width="2883" height="1622" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="time-to-prove-your-worth">Time to prove your worth!<a href="#time-to-prove-your-worth" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Time to prove your worth!" title="Direct link to Time to prove your worth!">​</a></h2><p>We hope you will all enjoy this brand-new game mode and the free Versus room! Are you still looking for some people to challenge in Versus mode? Then you should definitely join our official <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a>. You can also find us over on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PlayEscapeSimulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a> where you can also talk about all things Escape Simulator. We hope to see you there!</p><h1>Full Changelog</h1><details open="" class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="false"><summary><h4>New Content</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>3, 2, 1, Race! Two Versus specific rooms just landed in the game.</li><li>Immerse yourself in Versus mode with new customization options featuring 2 racer outfits.</li><li>Try the new <strong>Random Game finder</strong> if you can't find players to play with.</li><li>Use Versus props in the room editor to create thrilling racing rooms.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor &amp; Workshop</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>New Roulette Logic Prop! Finally some randomness. Activate one random target from the Targets list!</li><li>Camera movement speed setting! Now you can modify the camera movement speed setting while holding right-click and scrolling. Use shift/ctrl while moving to temporarily modify
the speed.</li><li>Added tooltips for all targets. Now you can tell which target is which by setting its Descriptive name and checking the tooltip.</li><li>Right-click prop selection window UX fixes. Modified when the window is closed, how it reacts to other right-clicks, right-clicking over gizmo, and more.</li><li>No more double-clicking after using the prop search field.</li><li>Fixed highlighting hovered props behind the transform gizmo which cannot be selected.</li><li>Fixed some props rotations.</li><li>Fixed some props being in multiple groups.</li><li>Fixed loading older rooms not opening due to wrong serialized data.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Tweaks</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added a new Host screen with additional options.</li><li>Added an option to change lobby options while already in a lobby.</li><li>Added an option to choose game difficulty in the lobby - Normal or Hard.</li><li>Added a new hover outline type that is less intrusive. You can change it in Options -&gt; Hover Effect Type.</li><li>Added interaction when clicking the dial that moves the dial for one step.</li><li>Changed versioning system to one number, removing prefix 1.0. For example, v1.0.27288n became v27288n.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Level Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed game crash when spamming water turning on and off in "The Lab".</li><li>Removed Steam Cats in Time popup in "Cats in time".</li><li>Fixed not exiting zoom on specific locks in "Leonardo's Workshop".</li><li>Fixed the wrong lock click direction in "70's Room" and "Treasure Island".</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Core Game Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed flashing objects when selecting them in the inventory.</li><li>Fixed custom models changing size in certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed invisible items when being dragged in zoom.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you could lose an item when spamming click on a zoomed item while throwing it out.</li><li>Items no longer shrink if you leave zoom while they animate.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you could duplicate an item while spamming E and changing the item via the numpad.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you could end some interactions too soon if you click alt.</li><li>Added an error screen if you try to enter a lobby with corrupted data or the lobby doesn't exist anymore.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>UI Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed Steamdeck UI bugs in the co-op screen.</li><li>Fixed UI bug where some dropdowns would have extra white elements on edges.</li><li>Fixed a rare case of UI overlapping after finishing the room ("Use" was behind room stats on the top right).</li><li>Fixed buttons staying highlighted in the in-game menu when exiting the menu with ESC.</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Versus Hotfix #1</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Versus Core</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed freeze if you are playing versus mode with a room that has an eject slot at the beginning of the map</li><li>Removed "You Lost!" message if you are left alone in a versus map.</li><li>Versus trophy screen is visually much more consistent across all maps.</li><li>Fixing freeze at Versus rooms where the game would freeze if other players disconnect at the trophy screen.</li><li>Fixed bug where versus leaderboards would display 1 instead 10.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Versus Rooms</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Adjusted lasers in "Versus Apprentice" room so its easier to see if you finished the puzzle</li><li>Adjusted hints for "Versus Apprentice" room.</li><li>Adjusted laser block time in "Versus Apprentice" so it's a more fluid feel.</li><li>Adjusting Japanese translations in "Versus Apprentice".</li><li>Fixing bug where rotating cubes could be rotated at a weird angle in "Versus Apprentice".</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Random Lobby</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Adjusted random lobbies so they look for additional regions for a match.</li><li>Searching for a random lobby now shows "Connecting" panel and disallows click spamming random matches.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Level Specific</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixing freeze in "The Elevator" in coop when picking up a key.</li><li>Fixed wrong player spawn locations in "The Metaverse" in versus mode.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Other</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Removed token UI in rooms that have no tokens.</li><li>Fixing soft lock if you leave a zoom</li><li>Fixing bug where big items would clip through a player when entering a slot.</li><li>Changed "Dynamic Walkthrough" Steam tag to "Versus".</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>versus</category>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Treasure Island Update]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2023/06/22/treasure-island-update</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2023/06/22/treasure-island-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[X marks the spot! 🗺️]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="x-marks-the-spot-️">X marks the spot! 🗺️<a href="#x-marks-the-spot-️" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to X marks the spot! 🗺️" title="Direct link to X marks the spot! 🗺️">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="X Marks the Spot" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/banner-e1526320c68a9e171a453d434d71d60f.png" width="800" height="450" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Ahoy there, scurvy dogs! Get ready for another swashbucklin’ adventure in Escape Simulator! Our latest free update sets sail to Treasure Island, where you can explore a vast island that’s rumored to hide an invaluable treasure. The Treasure Island update also comes with a matching outfit and an additional soundtrack to accompany you on your quest for booty! Alongside this exciting content, we've made a whole bunch of fixes and additions, which you can find in the full changelog below. So set sail and join the hunt for the hidden treasure!</p><p>Visit the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1435790/Escape_Simulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam Store</a> to check out the game!</p><p>To celebrate the launch of this new room, we are offering a 25% discount on Escape Simulator. It's the perfect time to get the game for yourself or gift it to a friend!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="25% Discount" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/roadmap-da6a4f4ad34e7cbfe535f5bda4088f94.png" width="2883" height="1622" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>With this update, we unveil two secrets from our roadmap for 2023! Escape Simulator VR is coming soon, allowing you to experience all the base game rooms in virtual reality. You'll soon be able to explore Treasure Island up close! Help us by adding Escape Simulator VR to your <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2440240/Escape_Simulator_VR/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam wishlist</a> and stay tuned for more exciting announcements.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="avast-ye-landlubbers">Avast, ye landlubbers!<a href="#avast-ye-landlubbers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Avast, ye landlubbers!" title="Direct link to Avast, ye landlubbers!">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Treasure Island" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/screenshot-bfb9ddde09fa0da34dac1612224aa644.png" width="1837" height="1127" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We hope you're all set to embark on this adventure to Treasure Island, and we can't wait to hear your thoughts on this brand-new room! Our roadmap for 2023 promises even more updates, so stay tuned for upcoming announcements. In the meantime, feel free to join our official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PlayEscapeSimulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subreddit</a> to be part of the Escape Simulator community. See you there, adventurers!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="full-changelog">Full changelog<a href="#full-changelog" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Full changelog" title="Direct link to Full changelog">​</a></h2><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>New content</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Shiny new room: Treasure Island</li><li>New character customization options for Treasure Island</li><li>New Puzzle logic prop for the room editor</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>General fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Saves are now in Json format.</li><li>Fixed some RAM memory leaks.</li><li>Reduced size of the game.</li><li>Objects cannot enter two slots by throwing.</li><li>More performant Mirrors.</li><li>Mirrors work in zoom.</li><li>CJK Fonts now work on Steam deck.</li><li>Added zoom in hint on the controller when possible to zoom in.</li><li>Internal rework of sliding puzzles for fewer errors.</li><li>Fixed all small UI input offsets in levels.</li><li>Added rounded corners where they were missing.</li><li>Next Level now works across all extra rooms.</li><li>Particles are now hidden in ghost placement objects.</li><li>Changed the way items interact with the physics engine, resulting in more fluid collisions.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Co-op fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Every puzzle now has a name.</li><li>Every sent data packet is smaller, improving Co-op performance.</li><li>Rework of syncing object poses, resulting in smoother gameplay in larger rooms.</li><li>Fixing crashing when interacting with items with weird parenting in custom rooms.</li><li>Items are now spawned into the host's inventory when a player disconnects.</li><li>Items are now thrown from the hand, resulting in smoother animation.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Workshop &amp; Room editor fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Audio crashes with sound props fixed.</li><li>Better handling of audio on large rooms.</li><li>Zoomables now have free camera position.</li><li>Walkthrough text cutting off and not saving fixed.</li><li>Editor Tutorial rooms - fixed teleport buttons.</li><li>Fixed Game freeze on dragging objects to slots.</li><li>Locks don't need to trigger sound props with a 1.</li><li>Open walkthrough with H for testing in the room editor.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Level specific fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed "The Top" bug where multiple people would "solve" slider puzzle.</li><li>Far objects in "The Top" are now pingable in coop.</li><li>Orange is more orange than ever in "Leonardo's Workshop".</li><li>Fixed wrong syncing of balls in "Chamber of Danger".</li><li>Better colliders in the clock of "The Underground Lab".</li><li>Fixed keypad position in "The Lab".</li><li>Fixed "Decompression Chamber" bug where the tool would fly in the air after using it.</li><li>Reduced the number of net packets sent in "Space Walk", resulting in smoother gameplay.</li><li>Better controller handling of rope puzzle on "The Engine Room".</li><li>Fixed disk syncing in "The Engine Room".</li><li>Better controller handling of the final puzzle on "The Helm".</li><li>Better colliders in the sink of "The Saloon".</li><li>As always, we've added more bugs to fix later.</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leonardo's Workshop Update]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2023/03/08/leonardos-workshop-update</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2023/03/08/leonardos-workshop-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Splash]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Splash" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/splash-cb43bc90a38a6b84ee243895e6421db3.png" width="800" height="450" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="do-you-have-the-skills-to-beat-this-challenge">Do you have the skills to beat this challenge?<a href="#do-you-have-the-skills-to-beat-this-challenge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Do you have the skills to beat this challenge?" title="Direct link to Do you have the skills to beat this challenge?">​</a></h2><p>It's no secret that Leonardo da Vinci was a man of many skills. Not only was he a masterful painter, but he also took a great interest in many other subjects such as science, engineering, sculpting...and apparently puzzles as well! So with that knowledge in mind, do you think you will be able to outsmart the great Leonardo da Vinci himself? We would definitely like to see you try!</p><p>If you think you've got what it takes, try solving our new <strong>free</strong> room Leonardo's Workshop, which is out now! This additional room is part of a free update, which also includes a full translation into Italian! Of course we are also adding another outfit and a soundtrack so you can get fully immersed in the world of Leonardo da Vinci. Finally, this update brings a whole bunch of optimizations to the Room Editor, including faster room loading. A full changelog can be found at the end of this announcement. 👇</p><p>To celebrate the launch of this new room, you can now get Escape Simulator with a <strong>25% discount</strong>! So if you haven't purchased the game yet or want to gift it to a friend, now would be the perfect time to do so! </p><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1435790/Escape_Simulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://store.steampowered.com/app/1435790/Escape_Simulator/</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="leonardos-workshop-is-open-for-business">Leonardo's Workshop is open for business!<a href="#leonardos-workshop-is-open-for-business" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Leonardo's Workshop is open for business!" title="Direct link to Leonardo's Workshop is open for business!">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Splash" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/flythrough-34dfe29299fae512c2f6eb41b83ebc21.gif" width="528" height="264" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We truly hope all of you will enjoy this brand-new update and we can't wait to hear your thoughts on the new room. Looking for a co-op partner or just want to chat about our game? Then please feel free to join us over on our <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> or our <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PlayEscapeSimulator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subreddit</a> for more Escape Simulator fun! Make sure to stay tuned in the meantime, because we still have plenty of stuff planned for the (near) future.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="full-changelog">Full changelog<a href="#full-changelog" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Full changelog" title="Direct link to Full changelog">​</a></h2><details open="" class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="false"><summary><h4>New Content</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>New room. Find all secrets in Leonardo's Workshop!</li><li>New language; Italian. <em>Ciao!</em></li><li>Expanding your fashion choices with new "Leonardo's Workshop" outfits.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>General fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Daily picks evolve in Trending. Displaying the top 6 rooms of the last week.</li><li>Better RAM usage when loading rooms.</li><li>Better handling of wiping systems in "The Office" and "The Elevator".</li><li>Hovering over Slidable now shows a drag crosshair.</li><li>Fixing bug where you couldn't throw some items in slots.</li><li>Fixed some hairs so they are fading in coop mode.</li><li>Better co-op syncing in "The Lab".</li><li>The furnace gate in "The Engine Room" is disabled when opened the first time.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>More fixes for the controller</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>General stability.</li><li>Better Slidable handling.</li><li>items popup work with both thumbsticks.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Workshop changes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Better handling of Activator components in coop levels.</li><li>Added Custom walkthrough for customs levels.</li><li>Remade publish screen.</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wild West DLC & Big Bug Fix Update]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/12/08/wild-west-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/12/08/wild-west-dlc</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Splash]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Splash" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/header-4733ace4e30d5bd6fab682bcc24ff672.jpg" width="460" height="215" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="yeehaw-the-new-dlc-is-here">Yeehaw! The new DLC is here!<a href="#yeehaw-the-new-dlc-is-here" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Yeehaw! The new DLC is here!" title="Direct link to Yeehaw! The new DLC is here!">​</a></h2><p>We hope you're ready for a rootin'-tootin' escape adventure, because the <strong>Wild West DLC</strong> is out now! The Wild West DLC features four additional rooms: The Sheriff's Office, The Saloon, The Bank and the Post Office and The Train. Of course, you'll need some matching clothes to fit the occasion, so the DLC also includes two new outfits. Will you dress up as a sleek sheriff or a rugged outlaw? The choice is yours! </p><p>Ready to embark on this new adventure? Don't wait a minute longer and purchase the Wild West DLC <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2175260/Escape_Simulator_Wild_West_DLC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">right here</a>! YEEHAW!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="all-cleaned-up-">All cleaned up! 🧹<a href="#all-cleaned-up-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to All cleaned up! 🧹" title="Direct link to All cleaned up! 🧹">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Big Bug Fix" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/bigBugFix-f255cdedd11dc10a147945c4bff43abe.png" width="800" height="450" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Bugs are pesky little things, aren't they? Before you know it, you have an infestation on your hands. Obviously, no one wants that for Escape Simulator! That is why all of the bug reports and general feedback we receive from our community is always extremely valuable to us.</p><p>Over the past few weeks, we have been working hard to address as many of your reports as possible.  To make sure you get the fully optimized Wild West experience, we are also releasing an additional update today. This update should fix a great amount of known bugs and issues. Through this update, we hope to enhance the Escape Simulator experience even further. It is of great importance to us that anyone who supports our game gets to fully enjoy Escape Simulator as it was intended. You can find a full overview of the different bugs that were addressed here.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="come-hang-out-with-us">Come hang out with us!<a href="#come-hang-out-with-us" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Come hang out with us!" title="Direct link to Come hang out with us!">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Big Bug Fix" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/flythrough-9c5bc7ad189ab1bbb60afee1cfa12811.gif" width="600" height="216" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>To celebrate the release of the Wild West DLC, we are doing another Escape Simulator livestream today at 8PM CET! We'll be answering any questions you might have about the new DLC. Additionally, we will announce the two lucky winners of the <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/1435790/announcements/detail/3481873895634983781" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wild West DLC fanart contest</a>! Be sure to tune in and come hang out with us on Steam, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitch</a> or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@PineStudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a>!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="stay-up-to-date">Stay up to date!<a href="#stay-up-to-date" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Stay up to date!" title="Direct link to Stay up to date!">​</a></h2><p>We still have a lot more exciting things planned for Escape Simulator, so be sure to keep an eye out on our channels for future updates! Can't get enough of the game and want to talk to other players or room builders? Then please consider joining our official <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PlayEscapeSimulator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subreddit</a>! In the meantime, we want to thank all of you once again for your ongoing support. We hope everyone will enjoy these four new rooms and we can't wait to hear what you think!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Train" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/train-3ddf9abf97e6760e920130b505f34063.gif" width="600" height="337" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><em>All aboard the hype train!</em></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="full-changelog">Full changelog<a href="#full-changelog" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Full changelog" title="Direct link to Full changelog">​</a></h2><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Added Wild West DLC</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Various Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added rich presence for Graveyard and 70s Room</li><li>Loading to the second Tutorial room shouldn't freeze the game</li><li>Fixed UI glitches on Publish popup window</li><li>Items should not appear on top of options anymore</li><li>Turnable speed is now consistent on any FPS</li><li>Several fixes for French, German, Portuguese, and Spanish</li><li>Improve chat profanity filter: no longer as aggressive as before</li><li>Added option to disable profanity filter</li><li>Fixed turnable pieces and other pieces being pickupable</li><li>Removed memory leak when loading multiple levels in one session</li><li>Fixed bug where UI behind interactive object would take input</li><li>Added more skin colors</li><li>Fixed Santa's hat and Twitch's hat not being visible</li><li>Added more bugs for later fixing ^^</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Co-op</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Characters' colors in a co-op are much more consistent</li><li>Fixed scales in co-op</li><li>Fixed zoomable in co-op</li><li>Stop the timer when disconnected in the co-op</li><li>Voice beta tag removed</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Level Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Redesigned zoetrope puzzle in Lost Spirits</li><li>Fixed eraser in The Office</li><li>Fixed mop in The Elevator</li><li>Fixed hints on The Office, Executive Office, and Cats in Time</li><li>Fixed throttle in The Helm</li><li>Pipes eventually sync if they desync in Space Walk</li><li>Fixed cannons staying open after firing in The Crew Quarters</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Controller</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed look achievements with controller</li><li>Better dial handling on the controller</li><li>Better joystick handling on the controller</li><li>Fixing UX and UI for the controller</li><li>Added trail when moving the cursor with the controller</li><li>More solid interactions with "A" and "RT".</li><li>Two thumbsticks are interchangeable in various interactions</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed transparent plane repeats edge pixels</li><li>Only one matryoshka doll</li><li>Custom skybox seams fixed</li><li>The download texture button no longer overwrites old images</li><li>Fixed the 'Open UGC Folder' button for Mac</li><li>There are no longer weird lit lines in workshop levels </li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Wild West Hotfix #1</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed Chinese translation for the Faro table</li><li>Changed token location for the safe one</li><li>Fixed some physics issues</li><li>Fixed hints in the Saloon</li><li>More visible "dead bet" note in the Saloon room</li><li>Fixed issues with colliders. </li><li>Some important items now respawn if lost</li><li>Added a few missing names</li><li>Polished a few interactions</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Wild West Props</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Wild West Room Editor props</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added the Wild West props!</li><li>Fixed the house not winning in The Saloon</li><li>Fixed sound positioning for preset 3D sounds</li><li>Added a plant category for props </li><li>A few more smaller fixes</li></ul></div></div></details><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="-pine-team">♥ Pine team<a href="#-pine-team" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to ♥ Pine team" title="Direct link to ♥ Pine team">​</a></h3>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
            <category>dlc</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Halloween update]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/10/25/halloween-update</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/10/25/halloween-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Things are about to get spooky! 👻]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="things-are-about-to-get-spooky-">Things are about to get spooky! 👻<a href="#things-are-about-to-get-spooky-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Things are about to get spooky! 👻" title="Direct link to Things are about to get spooky! 👻">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Flythrough" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/flythrough-d5978daf48d81883738b34280cedef52.gif" width="800" height="335" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We hope you're ready to solve some more tricky puzzles, because the Halloween update for Escape Simulator is <strong>OUT NOW</strong>! This update features a brand-new room set in an eerie looking graveyard. Will you be able to solve its many mysteries? 🔍</p><p>To really add to the spooky vibes, the new Graveyard level is accompanied by a special soundtrack! But wait, you didn't think we'd let you celebrate Halloween without a matching outfit, right? Of course not! That's why the Halloween update also features a new customization option that allows you to turn your character into a ghostly version of itself!
We also did more than <strong>600 fixes and quality-of-life improvements</strong> for the game. You can read the whole changelog below.🔽</p><p>We hope you will all enjoy this free update to celebrate the month of Spooktober! In case you missed it, we recently announced the <strong>next big DLC</strong> for Escape Simulator as well. The <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2175260/Escape_Simulator_Wild_West_DLC/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wild West DLC</a> is set to release in December, so make sure to wishlist it! This way, you'll receive a notification as soon as it's out. In the meantime, feel free to join us on our official <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PlayEscapeSimulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a> to talk about all things Escape Simulator. Hope to see you there!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="full-changelog">Full changelog<a href="#full-changelog" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Full changelog" title="Direct link to Full changelog">​</a></h2><details open="" class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="false"><summary><h4>New content</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Brand new haunted room: Graveyard.</li><li>You have the option to be a ghost in multiplayer levels!</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Rooms fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>70's Room: Fixed polaroid flash.</li><li>The Engine Room: Fixed using fire extinguisher with a controller.</li><li>The Top: a rotating object should feel better in singleplayer and multiplayer.</li><li>The Elevator: there is a reset button for the circular puzzle in case you get stuck.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Lua</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Better error handling, the log will show on what line the error occurred</li><li>Added support for Slidables in Lua</li><li>Lua fixed can't enter negative indexes for locks</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Introducing the all new prop behaviour ✨The Slidable✨ </li><li>Added button to fix workshop item id in the publish room menu</li><li>Controller slot interaction should work better</li><li>Pickables now work on zoomables</li><li>Fixed crashing on copy/duplicate and undo</li><li>Unlock input on locks should now work for continuous and fixed locks</li><li>Fixed importing a display prop with textures breaks the room</li><li>Only the display logic prop needs the transparent order offset checkmark</li><li>Custom models material fixes</li><li>Fixed laser effect rendering on screen</li><li>Sounds shouldn't continue on loading next episode</li><li>Fixed finish screen exit room buttons</li><li>Keypad prop reset button fixed</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Other features &amp; fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>There is a new news section. It will display important updates to the game.</li><li>Better controller handling.</li><li>Better controller slot interaction.</li><li>Voice chat is now much more reliable.</li><li>Proximity chat is now working properly.</li><li>Fixed a bug where removing an item from inventory could crash the game.</li><li>Fixed placement of the held item on all camera FOVs.</li><li>filtered chat messages are no longer just ignored</li><li>Item can no longer be pinned during animation.</li><li>There are avatars in UI showing who is speaking in voice chat.</li><li>Sliders have been improved across the game. They should feel better in singleplayer and are synced better in multiplayer.</li><li><strong>617 commits</strong> of bug fixes and quality-of-life improvements!</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[70's room]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/09/22/seventies-room</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/09/22/seventies-room</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Peace out! ✌️]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="peace-out-️">Peace out! ✌️<a href="#peace-out-️" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Peace out! ✌️" title="Direct link to Peace out! ✌️">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Room" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/room-2c6bbb1923693111b8a989c45ac798db.png" width="1286" height="619" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We hope you like lava lamps and disco balls, because it's time to go back to the 70's. That's right, we're releasing a brand-new room for Escape Simulator <strong>today</strong>! In order to escape from this incredibly cozy looking room, you'll need to know your way around some 'ancient' technology, such as cassette decks and a very retro game console. So vintage!</p><p>That's not all, though! The <strong>70's room</strong> is part of our latest update, which also contains a whole bunch of additional features for the room editor. We hope you're excited to start using these features, builders! Additionally, this update contains the following tweaks:</p><ul><li>Different internal level packing, the game should be smaller on disk. It's about 5GB smaller than before!</li><li>New hint system that tracks what puzzle you are playing and gives relevant hints</li><li>Localization fixes</li><li>Separated settings and save files. Only save is uploaded to cloud save, meaning settings is local to the machine.</li><li>Faster performance mode for custom rooms</li><li>Disable shadows option has 2x increased FPS in built-in rooms</li><li>Chat key is can be rebound to different key</li><li>Changed how zooms are calculated, some items are now bigger for better clarity</li><li>Better controller support</li><li>Better support for breaking hanging objects (plants, mirrors, ...)</li><li>Its easier to use slots with controller with new Controller-Slot interaction UX</li></ul><p>More patch notes can be found right here!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="more-rooms-to-check-out-">More rooms to check out! 👀<a href="#more-rooms-to-check-out-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to More rooms to check out! 👀" title="Direct link to More rooms to check out! 👀">​</a></h2><p>We really hope you'll enjoy this free update and that you'll continue to look forward to even more rooms in the future! We're working really hard to bring a bunch of additional rooms to the game and of course we're always trying to further improve upon the room editor as well. For all things Escape Simulator, please consider joining our dedicated <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord community</a> or come talk to us over on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PlayEscapeSimulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a>.</p><h1>Patch Notes</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Game</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Different internal level packing, the game should be smaller on disk. It's about 5GB smaller than before!</li><li>New hint system that tracks what puzzle you are playing and gives relevant hints</li><li>Localization fixes</li><li>Separated settings and save files. Only save is uploaded to cloud save, meaning settings is local to the machine.</li><li>Faster performance mode for custom rooms</li><li>Disable shadows option has 2x increased FPS in built-in rooms</li><li>Chat key is can be rebound to different key</li><li>Changed how zooms are calculated, some items are now bigger for better clarity</li><li>Better controller support</li><li>Better support for breaking hanging objects (plants, mirrors, ...)</li><li>Its easier to use slots with controller with new Controller-Slot interaction UX</li><li>Brand oldie-but-goldie room: 70's Room </li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor Features</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added Cats In Time room props</li><li>Added 2 transparency props (the reign of the sticker is over)</li><li>Added number, letter and symbol props</li><li>Added the Display logic prop</li><li>Added a functional keypad prop</li><li>Added a button for exporting default prop textures</li><li>The 'Finish' logic prop can now be used to load other custom rooms, you can continue your stories through other rooms</li><li>Added options on the 'Finish' logic prop for setting the final camera position</li><li>Hide props while editing the room with 'H' or 'Shift + H'</li><li>Right click on a collection of props and select one by name</li><li>Added a 'Use Rigidbody' checkmark to Animations/Buttons to help with physics prop interactions</li><li>Added a button for fixing custom texture sizes for better compression</li><li>New room option added: 'Require post processing'</li><li>Lua activator API added</li><li>Teleport, Sound, Fog, Post Processing and Skybox can now be triggered by any value except for zero (enabled by resetting the connection)</li><li>Community room lighting option added</li><li>Locks now have a reset pin ("R"), target it with any value but zero to reset the lock values to zero (for lua, just target the index with -400)</li><li>Locks also now have a master unlock pin ("U"), target it with any value but zero to unlock the lock (for lua, just target the index with -500)</li><li>Right click on a prop to show a list of all selectable props under the cursor, change prop names to easily differentiate between props when selecting this way</li><li>Logic props that are based on locks (Sound, Fog, etc.) can now be triggered by any number except zero</li><li>Added a transparency order offset setting for transparent objects, change this if you want some transparent objects to render in front/back of other transparent objects</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Smoother animations in zooms</li><li>Visibility Activator delay removed to help with desync</li><li>Fixed an issue where Visibility Activators didn't disable all colliders on some props</li><li>Fixed issue with importing props from other rooms, references to non copied props are removed</li><li>Pickable animations can now be set as slot keys</li><li>Animations and buttons can no longer be picked up in zoom without using the pickable checkmark</li><li>Fixed a hole in a halloween wall</li><li>Fixed ambience sounds not stopping when starting other music sounds</li><li>Transitioning to post processing with a disabled color filter now correctly transitions to no color filter</li><li>Fixed removing prop links from slots when changing prop behaviour and undo</li><li>Fixed reflection change on further away floors and props</li><li>Fixed activator triggering for each player on start</li><li>Exit zoom is no longer blocked by buttons and animations</li><li>Fixed embedded gltf falsely reporting missing models</li><li>Slot keys can now have triggers as children</li><li>Fixed issue with slot keys disappearing when ejected while in zoom</li><li>Fixed Visibility Activator enabling collider renderers on some props
-Zoomables can no longer have the pin button</li><li>Click and drag selection now targets all props, use alt + click and drag to target only the root parent object</li><li>Clone onChange updates now correctly update when animations are completed and not at the start</li><li>UI text fixes, some translations and hints added</li><li>Rect selection now selects all objects instead of only parents, use ALT + click and drag to only select parents</li><li>Fixed pivots for certain props (to see the change replace the old prop with the new version of it)</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>70's Room Hotfix #1</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Game</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added missing textures for translations</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>70's Room Hotfix #2</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Game</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>70's Room visual bug fixes</li><li>70's Room translation fixes</li><li>Translation fixes on some levels in Steampunk DLC</li><li>More solid monitor selector option</li><li>Fixed transparency clipping issue for custom rooms</li><li>Better right click movement in the room editor</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Room Editor 2.0]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/06/06/room-editor-two</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/06/06/room-editor-two</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[PATCH NOTES]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="patch-notes">PATCH NOTES<a href="#patch-notes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to PATCH NOTES" title="Direct link to PATCH NOTES">​</a></h2><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li><p>Added Light prop, now you can add custom lightning and it comes with better performance! </p></li><li><p>Added post-processing prop, change the ambient of your rooms. </p></li><li><p>Added zoomable behavior, no more zooming to locks </p></li><li><p>Added scripting custom rooms using Lua</p></li><li><p>More flexible than current setup, but you Lua programming knowledge is required. </p></li><li><p>Added Custom Drag behavior specifically for scripting. It gives you more control over object interactions.</p></li><li><p>Added loading custom models as props, you can create musical instruments using primitive objects or import one from .gltf file! </p></li><li><p>UX tweak: Changed from behavior buttons to a dropdown (Button, Animation, Turnable,...)</p></li><li><p>Menu UI scale fix for smaller screens </p></li><li><p>Added Discord Rich Presence, show others what awesome rooms you are playing</p></li><li><p>scripting props need to be enabled in the room config - only to view them in the menu, doesn't affect loading or saving</p></li><li><p>exposed the Vector3 and Quaternion class for static methods</p></li><li><p>now it's possible to lua functions to chat so players can trigger them</p></li><li><p>access to player IDs + teleport specific players</p></li><li><p>importing a lua object should now copy the lua file as well</p></li><li><p>collider dropdown added - None/Box/ConvexMesh/ConcaveMesh</p></li><li><p>shiny material issue fixed</p></li><li><p>cross platform loading of custom models fixed</p></li><li><p>new event: LuaCallType.ChatCommand when players write "/something"</p></li><li><p>Vector/Quaternion exposed</p></li><li><p>new functions for players: getAllPlayers, getLocalPlayer, getClosestPlayer, getMainPlayer</p></li><li><p>new function for teleporting: teleportPlayer</p></li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
            <category>room-editor</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steampunk DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/06/06/steampunk-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/06/06/steampunk-dlc</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Four brand new rooms for you to escape from in style!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe width="100%" height="500" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UbVeACVMOMY" title="Escape Simulator: Steampunk DLC - Release Trailer" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="four-brand-new-rooms-for-you-to-escape-from-in-style">Four brand new rooms for you to escape from in style!<a href="#four-brand-new-rooms-for-you-to-escape-from-in-style" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Four brand new rooms for you to escape from in style!" title="Direct link to Four brand new rooms for you to escape from in style!">​</a></h2><p>Get ready to solve a lot more puzzles, because the brand new <strong>Steampunk DLC</strong> is out now! Featuring four additional rooms that are filled to the brim with all kinds of curious machinery, this DLC is sure to get your gears grinding! To celebrate the arrival of this new content, both Escape Simulator and the Steampunk DLC are currently on sale! Additionally, you can now get all available content directly through the newly available Escape Simulator: Collector's Edition. This bundle is also available if you already own Escape Simulator and will add the content that you don't own yet to your Steam wallet. If you can't wait to board the Valor, then you can get the Steampunk DLC right <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1942100/Escape_Simulator_Steampunk_DLC/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>!</p><p>Each room in this DLC represents a different area of the steampunk airship ‘Valor’. Your journey through the Valor begins at The Crew Quarters, where you are awoken by a sudden explosion. You’ll have to make your way topside by putting out fires in The Engine Room and by taking care of the plants in The Greenhouse. Will you be able to make it to The Helm Room on time and regain control of the airship?</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="bring-your-community-rooms-to-the-next-level">Bring your community rooms to the next level!<a href="#bring-your-community-rooms-to-the-next-level" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Bring your community rooms to the next level!" title="Direct link to Bring your community rooms to the next level!">​</a></h2><p>In addition to all of the newly available Steampunk content, we are also releasing the free ‘<strong>Room Editor 2.0</strong>’ update today! This update will greatly expand the amount of possibilities for builders to make awesome community rooms! Additionally, builders will also get access to all of the Steampunk DLC assets, regardless of whether they bought the DLC or not. </p><p>To start things off, the latest version of the Room Editor now allows room builders to add all types of <strong>lighting</strong> to their rooms! With this feature, you’ll be able to really crank up the atmosphere in your creations. Additionally, we are adding post-processing options and a brand new model importer! With this model importer, builders are now able to add their own assets to their rooms, which will open up a world of opportunities!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="light" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/roomLight-97c5b4f4e6f18a508cf74b18f45f0a8d.gif" width="600" height="341" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Finally, the new Room Editor also adds a function which allows builders to make use of <strong>LUA scripting</strong>. Through scripting, builders will be able to modify the properties of their rooms to their own will. Like with the other added functions, we believe this will allow builders to further create rooms that are beyond our imagination!</p><p>For more information on the contents of the Room Editor 2.0 update, see the patch notes below!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="so-whats-next-for-escape-simulator">So what’s next for Escape Simulator?<a href="#so-whats-next-for-escape-simulator" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to So what’s next for Escape Simulator?" title="Direct link to So what’s next for Escape Simulator?">​</a></h2><p>We’ve been working hard to continue improving the Escape Simulator experience and there’s still a lot more awesome stuff coming up! That said, we are well aware that we couldn’t have done any of this without all of your support. We are truly glad to have such a great community and we hope you’ll continue to enjoy all of the upcoming updates. Currently we are still working on two free additional rooms that will be revealed at a later point, so be sure to keep an eye on our channels for more information! Finally, you can also join our official <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord channel</a> to talk about all things Escape Simulator. See you there?</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>New Light prop, now you can add custom lighting and it comes with better performance!</li><li>New post-processing prop, allowing you to change the ambience of your rooms.</li><li>New zoomable behavior, no more zooming to locks 🔒🔍</li><li>New scripting custom rooms using Lua</li><li>More flexible than current setup, but Lua programming knowledge is required.</li><li>New Custom Drag behavior specifically for scripting. It gives you more control over object interactions.</li><li>New loading custom models as props, you can create musical instruments using primitive objects or import one from .gltf file!</li><li>UX tweak: Changed from behavior buttons to a dropdown (Button, Animation, Turnable,...)</li><li>Menu UI scale fix for smaller screens</li><li>New Discord Rich Presence, show others which awesome rooms you are playing 🙂</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Steampunk hotfix #1</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Game</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed search in the in-game workshop not working</li><li>Fixed community rooms issue with teleport.</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Steampunk hotfix #2 &amp; Stempunk props</h1><p>Hello explorers!
We've listened to your feedback and fixed all critical bugs and issues reported in the last few days. Also, we've added <strong>all Steampunk assets</strong> to the room editor for everyone to use!
The update is now live, and here's a changelog of fixes that we can remember we did</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Game</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added new Steampunk props for Room Editor </li><li>Loading custom model without images fixed</li><li>Fixed cannon bug in Steampunk 1 (S1)</li><li>Fixed Omega DDR3/PC bug</li><li>Fix not seeing Steampunk image as a client if the DLC is not installed</li><li>Fixed puzzle box bug in S1</li><li>Added reset button sound in S1</li><li>Added better spawn points</li><li>The botanists should be happy with new updated plant names in S3</li><li>Multiple texture fixes in all rooms</li><li>Yellow crystals don't stack with bolts and screws anymore</li><li>Fixed box clipping in S1</li><li>The butterfly in the greenhouse now has a much better path</li><li>The propellers are now ok in the helm room</li><li>The radar doesn't have that one bright button anymore</li><li>The labyrinth in the engine room should work every time! </li><li>The seed shouldn't disappear from anyone! </li><li>Multiple optimizations </li><li>Added more bugs to fix later</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Steampunk hotfix #3</h1><p>Here's one more hotfix patch for the base game, Steampunk DLC and the Room Editor. We did a bunch of smaller fixes but here are the most important ones in 1.0.22752r version.</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>General changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added an option to remove timers</li><li>Fixed host can start a custom room before all players have installed it</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Steampunk DLC fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed some hint/key item tags and item names</li><li>Removed the trunk fruit from the tree</li><li>S1 lighters can no longer be picked up before solving the puzzle</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Teleport - "change rotation on teleport" checkmark is no longer inverted</li><li>Room title issue with some characters (like %) fixed</li><li>Fixed loading steampunk walls when creating a new room</li><li>Victorian key prop no longer has the unlocking audio when placed on the floor</li><li>Steampunk props - fixed some pivot and collider issues</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Steampunk hotfix #4</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>The Crew Quarters</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed cannonballs</li><li>Added water sounds</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>The Greenhouse</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed sign and flower faces</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>The Helm Room</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed textures</li><li>Fixed handles</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>When changing behavior on a prop (button/animation) the prop no longer gets removed from the activator targets</li><li>Dial value counts can no longer be set to 0</li><li>Importing props fixes:</li><li>Custom models are now copied when imported (but they need some time to load in and the prop isn't refreshed when they load in)</li><li>Importing audio, scripts and custom model files is blocked if the room is not saved</li><li>Fixed some models not loading paint-overs properly for custom models</li><li>Fixed steampunk walls on new room</li><li>Added a dropdown for the impostorClone update type: Never/OnChange/Always</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Other fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed unable to unsubscribe from custom room when the files are deleted locally</li><li>Male/Female character model colliders are now the same size</li><li>Scrollbar snaps to the top when entering workshop rooms menu and when searching</li><li>Fixed activator component desyncs in coop play</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>dlc</category>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One million players reached & Cats in time]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/05/02/milion-players-cats</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/05/02/milion-players-cats</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Milion]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Milion" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/milion-2ab26307ef1c5010a937cde98102c9c2.gif" width="600" height="337" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="to-our-1000000-players-thank-you">To our 1,000,000 players, thank you!<a href="#to-our-1000000-players-thank-you" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to To our 1,000,000 players, thank you!" title="Direct link to To our 1,000,000 players, thank you!">​</a></h2><p>We are both delighted and overwhelmed to share the amazing news that we have officially sold more than <strong>1 million copies of Escape Simulator</strong>. We never anticipated our game to reach this amount of success and we are incredibly thankful for each and every one of you! To celebrate this very special occasion, we are glad to announce that as of today, you will be able to play through a new official room! This new room pays tribute to one of the earlier PINE games: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1599880/Cats_in_Time/?utm_source=landing&amp;utm_campaign=ES_level" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cats In Time</a>! </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="can-you-make-it-in-time">Can you make it in time?<a href="#can-you-make-it-in-time" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Can you make it in time?" title="Direct link to Can you make it in time?">​</a></h2><p>In the new Cats In Time room, you will need to figure out how to repair Professor Tim Edger's time machine. However, this task won't be easy and you might just run into some strange issues while trying to fix the device. The clock's ticking! Will you be able to finish your task within thirty minutes? 😼</p><p>To celebrate this milestone, both <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1599880/Cats_in_Time/?curator_clanid=32969178" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cats In Time</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1435790/Escape_Simulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Escape Simulator</a> are both 20% off on Steam. Don't miss out on these discounts and make sure to tell all of your friends! 😉</p><iframe width="100%" height="500" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dze1DmQFDg0" title="Escape Simulator - Cats in Time Update" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-else-is-new">What else is new?<a href="#what-else-is-new" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What else is new?" title="Direct link to What else is new?">​</a></h2><p>Additionally, the latest update comes with a whole bunch of other new features and improvements!</p><p>First off, Escape Simulator now features <strong>in-game voice chat</strong>! We know that many of you were waiting for this feature, so we are happy to inform you that you will now be able to hear each other's voices without having to use external software. On that note, you are of course still free to join our official <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord channel</a> if you are in need of a co-op partner! We also added a brand new config screen to the room editor, which features a better option floor colliders and an option to adjust the visibility of both player nameplates and item nameplates. Finally, we added several other improvements to the Room Editor, such as the option to use multiselect all objects in a room, including locks! For the full list of updates, check the changelog below!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="get-ready-for-your-next-challenge">Get ready for your next challenge!<a href="#get-ready-for-your-next-challenge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Get ready for your next challenge!" title="Direct link to Get ready for your next challenge!">​</a></h2><p>To wrap things up, we want to once again thank everyone who participated in the HyperX and OMEN Build-A-Room contest and we hope all of you are looking forward to the next challenge. Speaking of which, more information on the next challenge will be shared VERY soon! 👀</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>General updates</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Texture compression in custom rooms</li><li>You can change the type of compression in options, if you select lower quality, custom rooms will run more smoothly</li><li>Main Menu using less RAM</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Multiplayer updates</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Better disconnecting in coop games</li><li>Offscreen ping indicators in coop games</li><li>Added voice chat</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor updates</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Brand new room config screen</li><li>You can use better floor colliders option</li><li>When using better floor colliders items respawn in inventory</li><li>Change visibility of player and item nameplates in your rooms</li><li>Added custom texture selection scrollbar</li><li>More tooltips! Every option has a tooltip describing what it does</li><li>Multiselect for everything. Yes, even locks!</li><li>Fixed bug where you couldn't click on items after moving with arrow keys</li><li>UX tweaks for large lists of targets</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HyperX & OMEN Gaming Showdown]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/04/07/hyperx</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/04/07/hyperx</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[CALLING ALL ROOM BUILDERS!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>CALLING ALL ROOM BUILDERS!</strong>
Starting today, Escape Simulator will be collaborating with <strong>HyperX</strong> and OMEN for a VERY special room building challenge! The winners of this challenge will be rewarded with a variety of products provided by both brands. See the full list of prizes below! </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Splash" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/splash-fdae78245475230d4a003624d25337af.gif" width="600" height="345" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>To get a chance of winning these awesome prizes you will need to build the <strong>ultimate gaming escape room</strong> with Escape Simulator’s in-game room editor! In order to build this ’Ultimate Game Room’, you will need to make use of a full set of assets that represent real-life HyperX and OMEN products. You can find these assets in the Room Editor. Submissions will be considered if they have been sent in before April 11, 2022 (6PM CEST / 9AM PT / 12PM ET)</p><p>We aim to announce the winners on <strong>Monday, April 25</strong>! As we want to play every room thoroughly, depending on the amount of submissions the picking of winners might take longer than expected. We will communicate this in a timely manner if this happens!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="-prizes-">🏆<strong> Prizes* </strong><a href="#-prizes-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to -prizes-" title="Direct link to -prizes-">​</a></h2><ul><li><strong>First Place:</strong> OMEN 16 laptop + HyperX peripheral range including Cloud Alpha Wireless headset, QuadCast S microphone, Alloy Origins 60 keyboard, Pulsefire Haste Wireless Black mouse, Pulsefire Mat RGB mousepad</li><li><strong>Second Place:</strong> Cloud Alpha Wireless headset</li><li><strong>Third Place:</strong> QuadCast S microphone</li><li><strong>Fourth Place:</strong> Alloy Origins 60 keyboard</li><li><strong>Fifth Place:</strong> Pulsefire Haste Wireless White</li><li><strong>Sixth Place:</strong> Pulsefire Haste Wireless Black</li><li><strong>Seventh, Eighth, Ninth, and Tenth Place:</strong> Pulsefire Mat RGB </li><li><strong>Community Choice:</strong> Cloud Alpha Wireless headset + Pulsefire Haste Wireless Black mouse + Pulsefire Mat RGB mousepad</li></ul><p>*Prizes are subject to change depending on availability at HyperX and OMEN.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="-rules">📑 <strong>Rules</strong><a href="#-rules" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to -rules" title="Direct link to -rules">​</a></h2><ul><li>Create a game room using (at least one) provided HyperX and OMEN asset.</li><li>To submit a room for the competition, you have to post a link to your room in the "#🏆challenges" channel in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/ss2ycVXpjT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pine Studio Discord</a>, or in <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/1435790/discussions/0/3272436223672916055/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this Steam forum thread</a>. </li><li>You can only submit<strong> one</strong> room. Multiple submissions will not be counted.</li><li>You are allowed to bug fix your room after submission, but not resubmit an entirely different room.</li><li>Copies of other players' rooms are not eligible.</li><li>Keep it fun/clean! No profanity, racism, hate speech, sexually suggestive, etc content. Rooms that might be considered offensive in any way or form will be disqualified.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="️-judging-criteria">⚖️ <strong>Judging Criteria</strong><a href="#️-judging-criteria" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to ️-judging-criteria" title="Direct link to ️-judging-criteria">​</a></h2><p>Rooms will be judged based on criteria such as the quality of the puzzles, level of innovation, visual appeal and more. See the <a href="https://forms.gle/ayZ5GXvSreGrykvs9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">full list of criteria (and points system) here</a>!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="room" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/room-32eba8768b00572459545612ba4be9cb.png" width="2560" height="1440" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="️-tips--tricks">⚒️ <strong>Tips &amp; Tricks</strong><a href="#️-tips--tricks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to ️-tips--tricks" title="Direct link to ️-tips--tricks">​</a></h2><ul><li>Go to Escape Simulator, "Workshop" button, "Your Rooms," and press "Create". This creates an empty room, and you can start building.</li><li>To get some help, you can look through "Tutorial Rooms" and learn the basics such as puzzles and animation.</li><li>Or you can watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y8p-C327wAw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">our tutorial video</a>.</li><li>Need some more inspiration? Then you should definitely check out the winners from our first <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1435790/view/3087774682030958698" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">‘Build-a-room’ challenge</a>!</li><li>Finally, you can also <a href="https://discord.com/invite/ss2ycVXpjT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">join our dedicated Discord community</a> to ask about anything you might need help with!</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="-how-do-i-submit-my-entry"><strong>🙋 How do I submit my entry?</strong><a href="#-how-do-i-submit-my-entry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to -how-do-i-submit-my-entry" title="Direct link to -how-do-i-submit-my-entry">​</a></h2><p>Submitting a room for the competition is very easy. Just post a link to your room in the "🏆challenges" channel in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/ss2ycVXpjT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pine Studio Discord</a>!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="-join-our-livestream-today">🎥 <strong>Join our livestream today!</strong><a href="#-join-our-livestream-today" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to -join-our-livestream-today" title="Direct link to -join-our-livestream-today">​</a></h2><p>Today (March 29) we will have a special livestream with <strong>live Q&amp;A</strong> so you can ask anything and everything about this competition or other Escape Simulator related questions!
The stream starts at 8pm CEST/11am PDT/1pm CDT. Hope to see you there!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="happy-building">Happy building!<a href="#happy-building" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Happy building!" title="Direct link to Happy building!">​</a></h2><p>We hope you are as excited about this competition as we are and we can’t wait to see all of your amazing creations! </p><hr><p>Also, a <strong>new small update</strong> is out now! </p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>New Gaming assets for room editor featuring HyperX and Omen products</li><li>Networking has more fail checks, which can result in error screens instead of game crashes</li><li>Co-op fix where you could stay zoomed in but the item disappears</li><li>Support for multiple controllers connecting and disconnecting</li><li>"Metaverse" co-op fixes</li><li>"Space Walk" translation fixes</li><li>Room editor duplicate room bug fix when changing languages</li><li>Room editor room renaming bug fix</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Hotfix #1</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed crash with wrong format workshop rooms (stuck on menu screen with % signs)</li><li>Fixed download and unsubscribe buttons</li><li>Egypt - Room #2 - Chamber of the Dead - fixed Scarab puzzle in multiplayer</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Language pack update]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/03/22/languages</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/03/22/languages</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[img]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="img" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/languages-415f7a9616a78588c5e9cec8af836112.png" width="2888" height="1440" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Merhaba! / ¡Hola! / Olá!</h1><p>The time has come for another big Escape Simulator update! Today we will be adding no less than <strong>five</strong> language options to the game. Once this update goes live, you will be able to play the entire game in Türk (Turkish), Español (Spanish), Español (Spanish Latin America), Português (Portuguese) and Português (Portuguese Brasil)! We know that a lot of you have been waiting very patiently for this specific update, so we are very glad to reveal that the wait is finally over!</p><h1>New publishing options 📝</h1><p>Additionally, we have completely reworked the 'Publish custom room screen'. This update includes several new options you can adjust when publishing your custom room to Steam Workshop. First off, you can now change the visibility settings of your room before publishing. This also allows you to publish your room directly from the Room Editor. Furthermore, you will be able to change the description of your room and add new Patch Notes. Lastly, this update also enables the option to add Steam Workshop tags to your room, which should make it much easier for other players to find exactly what they are looking for. 👀</p><h1>Additional updates and tweaks (v1.0.20730r)</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>New trigger option: Trigger when all players enter the trigger</li><li>New lock option: Added parity XOR and exclusive XOR</li><li>New hair options for Cori's dad 🙂</li><li>New languages</li><li>Game optimizations, should run more smoothly and take less memory</li><li>Loop animations soft-lock in custom rooms fixed</li><li>UX tweaks for controller and general feel of the game so it is more uniform</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Room Editor packs update]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/02/18/room-editor-packs</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2022/02/18/room-editor-packs</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Earlier this month, we asked our community to vote between four potential asset packages for the room editor. Out of these packages, The Alchemist package got the most votes by far. So now it's time for all of you to work your magic!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, we asked our community to vote between four potential asset packages for the room editor. Out of these packages, The Alchemist package got the most votes by far. So now it's time for all of you to work your magic!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Alchemist" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/alchemist-b1028c6536682904821e84934dba950d.png" width="1919" height="1079" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Additional Room Editor updates</h1><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-assets">New assets:<a href="#new-assets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New assets:" title="Direct link to New assets:">​</a></h3><ul><li>Skyboxes</li><li>New effects</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Alchemist" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/particles-c604320ab5844860b5773ef233b5a07d.gif" width="600" height="318" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-logic-items">New logic items:<a href="#new-logic-items" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New logic items:" title="Direct link to New logic items:">​</a></h3><ul><li>Open link: Players can open links to Steam, Steam Community, or Wikipedia URLs.</li><li>And/Or/XOR /Not gates on the Lock object</li><li>Activator that can enable or disable objects</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="features">Features:<a href="#features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Features:" title="Direct link to Features:">​</a></h3><ul><li>Button, Animation, Lock, Trigger, and Slot have new Output Value field that can be changed</li><li>Code optimizations</li></ul><h1>But wait, there's more!</h1><p>Finally, the latest update also includes:</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Steam Deck support</li><li>Internal rework of networking - it should work much better for the community rooms now!</li><li>Linux and Mac graphical fixes</li><li>Daily Picks rework</li><li>Added additional custom level packs</li><li>388 commits of tweaks and fixes</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Hotfix #1</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed missing assets in the existing community rooms (egyptian walls, boots)</li><li>Halloween props can now be painted</li><li>Trashcan issues fixed</li><li>Removed tokens from props</li><li>Fixed item rotations and names</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Hotfix #2</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed freeze when some items enter trashcans</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Christmas Update]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2021/12/29/santa</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2021/12/29/santa</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It's the holiday season in Escape Simulator!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's the holiday season in Escape Simulator!
Our elves worked super hard to finish the last update of 2021. The update brings so many cool features! </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-santas-workshop-room">New "Santa's Workshop" room<a href="#new-santas-workshop-room" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New &quot;Santa's Workshop&quot; room" title="Direct link to New &quot;Santa's Workshop&quot; room">​</a></h3><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Santa" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/santa-2cc3269822c44a909a38e96ab6a5cca3.gif" width="800" height="450" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>If you need a last-minute Christmas <strong>gift</strong>, it's a great time to grab Escape Simulator while it's 20% off!</p><p>We want to say <strong>happy holidays from the entire Pine team</strong>! Thank you for playing and supporting our work. We hope Escape Simulator will bring you closer to friends and family and make some fond memories. </p><p>Next week, we are taking our (well deserved) <strong>vacation </strong>to recharge our batteries and prepare for the exciting 2022. </p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>New Features</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>New "<strong>Santa's Workshop</strong>" level.</li><li>New "<strong>Daily Level</strong>" tab.</li><li><strong>Anti motion sickness</strong> options and "auto anti motion sickness" preset.</li><li>Steam input with support for different controllers and <strong>controller </strong>rebinding options.</li><li>More <strong>robust pins</strong>.</li><li>New Christmas <strong>hats</strong>!</li><li>More than <strong>250 commits</strong> of fixes and tweaks to the game!</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Smaller room file sizes when publishing rooms to the Workshop.</li><li>New 3D viewport gizmo that can help you navigate around.  </li><li>Object importer - now you can import objects and object groups from other rooms! </li><li>New animation options - now you can set pause for bounce and loop animations. </li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Santa's Workshop Hotfix #1</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>[Critical]<!-- --> Fixed controller bug that caused dragging puzzles not to be solvable if sensitivity was low.</li><li>Translation graphics fixes in Santa's Workshop.</li><li>Character no hair when wearing hats fixed.</li><li>Controller switching fixes.</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Santa's Workshop Hotfix #2</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Wrong resolution set when the game was starting</li><li>Fixed room editor problems with locks targeting locks</li><li>Fixed room editor rooms rendering Logic items when it shouldn't</li><li>Fixed token in Space Walk level</li><li>More small fixes to the game</li></ul><p>We also have some additions for Room Editor:</p><ul><li>New items! You will find new Omega corp. props</li><li>You can set item name</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>Santa's Workshop Hotfix #3</h1><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Changelog</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Small update, fixed some room editor and workshop room bugs.</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Omega room]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2021/10/29/omega</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2021/10/29/omega</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[New Official Room: The Lobby]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-official-room-the-lobby">New Official Room: The Lobby<a href="#new-official-room-the-lobby" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New Official Room: The Lobby" title="Direct link to New Official Room: The Lobby">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="omega1" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/omega1-32c871014b6c92baaa9435cb81cbf3ab.png" width="1919" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We're releasing the first room in the all-new "Omega Corporation" pack, which will join "Labyrinth of Egypt", "Adrift in Space" and "Edgewood Mansion" as the 4th room pack. And best of all, you get to play it for free! The rest of the rooms from the packs are going to come in the coming two months.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="spooky-season-calls-for-spooky-assets">Spooky season calls for spooky assets!<a href="#spooky-season-calls-for-spooky-assets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Spooky season calls for spooky assets!" title="Direct link to Spooky season calls for spooky assets!">​</a></h2><p>We're adding Halloween assets to the room editor. Enjoy the pumpkins and candy! :)</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="candy" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/candy-b9680cb6d27f08891d6f5ea827399854.png" width="744" height="517" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We've also added effects. You can now have things such as smoke, fire, and sparks in your rooms. Special logic fog component was also added so you can turn your environment spookiness to 11!</p><p>You can also see the video overview by our designated room designer Matija:</p><iframe width="100%" height="500" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wk1Z_AxdTUw" title="Escape Simulator - Halloween Room Editor Update" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-spooky-room-to-go-with-spooky-assets">A Spooky room to go with spooky assets!<a href="#a-spooky-room-to-go-with-spooky-assets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A Spooky room to go with spooky assets!" title="Direct link to A Spooky room to go with spooky assets!">​</a></h2><p>To test the assets, we've designed a spooky room. It requires 2+ players, and you can get it here:</p><p><a href="https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2638379672" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2638379672</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="full-changelog-108618">Full changelog (1.0.8618)<a href="#full-changelog-108618" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Full changelog (1.0.8618)" title="Direct link to Full changelog (1.0.8618)">​</a></h2><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Game</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added Omega Corporation room #1.</li><li>Custom rooms with textures on linux fixed!</li><li>Trash sticky fix</li><li>Net zoom fix</li><li>Trashcan name</li><li>Bug fixed where impostor is created on other player when one player takes item from the trash</li><li>Fixing s3 keypad desync and mp zooms</li><li>Fixed slot key scaling.</li><li>Fixing net buffer errors when sending syncRigidbody, optimize net messages</li><li>Space3 - storage room item positioning fixes</li><li>Audio Egypt1 &amp; Egypt2 removed some audio which caused errors</li><li>Audio / removed sounds from hanging plants and chandeliers because of errors</li><li>Egypt4 - pyramid slot added</li><li>Trashcan duplication on zoom fixed</li><li>Egypt2 - scarab puzzle mp other player couldn't continue dragging fixed</li><li>Collection item stays selected on throw and drop.</li><li>Better networking, fixed some reconnection issues.</li><li>Victorian1 - large vase broke into extra pieces fix</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Room Editor</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Added effects</li><li>Added Fog</li><li>Added Crumpled Paper and texture</li><li>Created new portal and placed old portal in obsolete props</li><li>Created icons and generated meta</li><li>Different footstep sound in custom levels</li><li>Fixed Stove colliders, added Effects to the IgnoreTrigger Layer, and fixed effect colliders, Created new icons</li><li>Fixed Toy closet colliders and V2Desk Colliders.</li><li>Clean outline on room reset.</li><li>Desk compound fix.</li><li>Halloween props, scripts, colliders and icons. </li><li>Added nav mesh obstacles to all props that were to big to move through. Added switches to chest-s and props that needed to be openable by default.</li><li>Different ghost material.</li><li>Trigger fixes.</li><li>End screen does not teleport players in custom rooms, a bit different end screen</li><li>Added new textures for basic shapes, fixed collider issues on v2desk, new Halloween prop icons. </li><li>Triggers can be triggered by switches (with rigidbodies)</li><li>Halloween walls</li><li>Vector3 property z fix.</li><li>Disable setting slot as a parent.</li><li>Set Lock prefab collider to isTrigger.</li><li>Autosave.</li><li>Card material editor fixes.</li><li>Teleport all players.</li><li>Remove temp publish rooms on init</li><li>Fixing duplicate workshop items</li><li>Fixing sorting &amp; editor rooms token UI removed</li><li>Sorting workshop rooms</li><li>Map editor fixing tags. Decor, carpets etc.</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>🚀 100 000 players! 🚀</h1><p>Over the weekend, we passed the number <strong>100 000 players</strong>! That's beyond awesome, and what better way to celebrate than by releasing a new room for you all to play! 😊</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-official-room-the-office">New Official Room: The Office<a href="#new-official-room-the-office" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New Official Room: The Office" title="Direct link to New Official Room: The Office">​</a></h2><p>It's time for the 2nd room in the Ω Corporation pack: The Office!* You're trapped in the office of an employee of secretive Ω Corporation, he had to be very <strong>very</strong> careful when he left you clues how to escape and get to the next room.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="omega2" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/omega2-164f794425a2940f328e646dc2b1a1df.jpg" width="1919" height="1079" class="img_ev3q"></p><ul><li>Right now, it's launching only in English. More languages for the whole Omega Corporation pack are coming next week.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="changelog-v1018958r">Changelog v1.0.18958r<a href="#changelog-v1018958r" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Changelog v1.0.18958r" title="Direct link to Changelog v1.0.18958r">​</a></h2><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Features</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Omega Corporation room #2 released!</li><li>RoomEditor: Dial, turnable - edit multiple.</li><li>RoomEditor: searching improvement, consider tags.</li></ul></div></div></details><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Fixes</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li>Fixed hint tint colors.</li><li>Rigidbody child object now animates directly, bypassing issues with physics. (Unity issue)</li><li>Room editor: removed normal map from medieval material, changed the size of medieval walls - Walls and props. </li><li>RoomEditor: deleting multiple objects fix.</li><li>Better logging for networking.</li><li>Join lobby if localPlayer disconnected</li><li>Download workshop item on play.</li><li>Not simulating physics until all players join.</li><li>Better syncing off rigidbodies that are important.</li><li>Removing scale in sending rigidbody data.</li><li>Networking now syncs buttons directly, without going through physics sync.</li></ul></div></div></details><h1>OMEGA ROOMS</h1><p>Hello explorers!
We have something special for you today. Omega Update is now LIVE! This is our biggest free update so far, and it brings a lot of new content.
<img loading="lazy" alt="all" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/all-fba56ed8209684dfae99f3623f7542b5.gif" width="1200" height="675" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Also, it's a great time to get Escape Simulator (for yourself or as a gift ;)) because the game is <strong>20% off</strong> this weekend!
<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1435790/Escape_Simulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://store.steampowered.com/app/1435790/Escape_Simulator/</a>
Thanks to all our <strong>beta testers</strong> and guys from our <a href="https://discord.gg/pinestudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> channel for the support! ♥</p><p>Enjoy the update!</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary><h4>Game</h4></summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ul><li><strong>3 new rooms</strong> that complete Omega Corp. theme</li><li><strong>French</strong> language</li><li><strong>German</strong> language </li><li>Full <strong>gamepad</strong> support</li><li>You can now add <strong>custom sounds</strong> to your workshop rooms </li><li>New co-op hosting mode that should <strong>fix the connection problem</strong> that some of you have </li><li>A lot of minor bug fixes</li></ul></div></div></details>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
            <link>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2021/07/31/welcome</link>
            <guid>https://superjura.github.io/ESDocs/blog/2021/07/31/welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Logo]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Logo" src="/ESDocs/assets/images/logo-a787db46d61bc18cfaebe975a2b77ee0.png" width="768" height="294" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Welcome to the Escape Simulator Game Blog!</h1><p>In this blog, we aim to provide you with the latest updates, news, and features about Escape Simulator, the ultimate escape room experience. We'll keep you informed about new game updates, captivating rooms, and other exciting developments in the game. Whether you're a seasoned escape artist or a newcomer looking for a brain-teasing challenge, our blog will guide you through the world of Escape Simulator. Join us on this adventure filled with mind-bending puzzles and the thrill of being an escape master. Let's embark on this journey together!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>pine</category>
            <category>hello</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>